Guide to the Arnold Genthe Photograph Collection [1895]-1942 (Bulk 1906-1927) PR 19
New-York Historical Society
Arnold Genthe Photograph Collection
[1895]-1942, (Bulk 1906-1927)
New-York Historical Society
Genthe, Arnold, 1869-1942
PR 19
33.34 Linear feet
The Arnold Genthe Photograph Collection primarily contains examples of Genthe's early work in San Francisco's Chinatown, later portraits of well-known personalities in the arts, politics, and society, classic photographs of Isadora Duncan and other early modern dancers, and both color and black-and-white landscapes of Long Island and Westchester, New York, and of international destinations such as Guatemala and Japan.
Provenance
A purchase, in 1943, from the estate of Arnold Genthe accounts for the bulk of the collection. Several prints of unknown provenance were donated at some point in the latter half of the 20th century to the New-York Historical Society. The Library of Congress donated the collection of nitrate and glass negatives to the N-YHS in 1954 and 1957.
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers.
Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to ten exposures of stable, unbound material per day. (Researchers may not accrue unused copy amounts from previous days.) Researchers on site may print out unlimited copies from microfilm reader-printer machines at per-exposure rates. See guidelines in Reading room for details.
Biographical Note
Photographer Arnold Genthe (1869-1942) emigrated in 1895 from his native Germany to San Francisco, California. A doctoral student of classical philosophy in Germany, Genthe impulsively decided, on the cusp of an academic career, to take a position as a tutor in San Francisco for a year. He fell in love with the city and ended up settling there, teaching himself photography and quickly gaining recognition for his views of Chinatown street life. After 1906, he switched his artistic focus mainly to portraits circles.
Genthe's portrait photography really came into its own when he moved his studio to Manhattan in 1911. There he ran in society circles, with subjects and friends often one and the same. Some of the great theater and film actresses of the day appeared in his portraits (Greta Garbo, Mary Pickford, Julia Marlowe), as did socialites such as Mary Astor and artists and writers like Childe Hassam, Jack London, and Ezra Pound. Early modern dancers were a favorite subject of his as well, and he captured such pioneers as Isadora Duncan, Ruth St. Denis, and Anna Pavlowa as they pushed social and cultural boundaries.
Never married, Genthe was seen as something of a ladies' man - indeed, he seemed never to lack female subjects for his portraits, some photographed in states of undress that even now might be considered risqué. An early 20th-century cartoon by Haig Patigan shows Genthe with three young "Gibson Girls" and is titled "Herr Doctor Taking Peaches"; another illustration, by Maynard Dixon, shows Genthe behind the camera, seemingly working his magic on a young woman in a filmy gown. Yet Genthe was not known as a cad; he seemed to have a true appreciation of the beauty and intellect of women young and old alike. Once, when asked to name the most beautiful woman he had ever photographed, he surprised his questioner by telling him it was the actress Eleanora Duse - when she was 64.
Genthe's many travels (to Latin America, the Far East, and Europe, which he photographed as well), add to what seems to have been a charmed and exotic life. He published a number of books of photographs, including The Book of the Dance, Pictures of Old Chinatown, and Impressions of Old New Orleans. A friend once said to him, "You certainly are a queer duck - a Don Juan, a Hermit Monk, a Chinese Sage, a University Professor - all rolled into one." To this he replied: "Well, maybe. Of this I am sure: I have never been bored, and I daresay I have had as much out of life as is coming to any man."
Scope and Content Note
The Arnold Genthe Photograph Collection spans the period from approximately 1895 to 1942 and primarily contains examples of Genthe's early work in San Francisco's Chinatown, later portraits of well-known personalities in the arts, politics, and society, classic photographs of Isadora Duncan and other early modern dancers, and both color and black-and-white landscapes of Long Island and Westchester, New York, and of international destinations such as Guatemala and Japan. The collection is divided into the following series: San Francisco Chinatown; Portraits; Landscapes; Dancers; Cats; and Negatives. Many of the prints are on Genthe's original mounts; about one-third are signed by Genthe and/or carry his studio label. When Genthe has given a photograph a title, that title is used. Otherwise, N-YHS has assigned a descriptive title, which appears in brackets, or has used the last and first names of the sitter for those portraits that are identified.
Arrangement
The collection has been arranged in the following six series:
Missing Title
Series I: San Francisco Chinatown
Series II: Portraits
Series III: Landscapes
Series IV: Dancers
Series V: Cats
Series VI: Negatives
Related Material
The bulk of the photographs and negatives found in Genthe's studio at his death are now at the Library of Congress, Prints and Photographs Division. Several thousand negatives are also housed at the Museum of the City of New York. Many museums and libraries around the country, including the California Historical Society, have prints by Genthe.
New York (N.Y.) -- Pictorial works.; Photographic prints.; Transparencies; negatives (photographs); Self-portraits; Portraits.; Japan -- Pictorial works.; Guatemala -- Description and travel -- Views.; Europe -- Description and travel -- Views.; Salt Lake City (Utah) -- Description and travel -- Views.; White Sulphur Springs (W. Va.) -- Description and travel -- Views.; Dancers -- Portraits; Celebrities -- Portraits; Actors -- Portraits.; Artists -- Portraits; Authors -- Portraits; Cats -- Photographs; Portrait photography; Chinese -- California -- San Francisco (Calif.) -- Photographs.; Streets -- California -- San Francisco -- Photographs.; Chinatown (San Francisco, Calif.) -- Pictorial works.; New Orleans (La.) -- Description and travel -- Views.; Long Island (N.Y.) -- Description and travel -- Views.; Millay, Edna St. Vincent, 1892-1950 -- Portraits; Morgan, J. P. (John Pierpont), 1867-1943 -- Portraits; Pickford, Mary, 1892-1979 -- Portraits; Flagg, James Montgomery, 1877-1960 -- Portraits; Garbo, Greta, 1905-1990 -- Portraits; Genthe, Arnold, 1869-1942; Hassam, Childe, 1859-1935 -- Portraits; London, Jack, 1876-1916 -- Portraits
- Series I: San Francisco Chinatown
  Scope and Contents note
  Series I is a collection of street scenes taken between about 1895 and 1906, during Arnold Genthe's residence in San Francisco. The earliest dated print is from 1898; most are approximately 13 by 9 inches in size. Photographs are arranged alphabetically by title or description.
  All of the prints feature Chinese Americans going about their daily lives on the streets of Chinatown. Many photographs are of children, captured alone or with adults, often dressed in ornate, imperial-Chinese clothing (adults are generally not attired in this ornate clothing). One whimsical shot shows a gay parade of Chinese children marching through the streets, each holding onto the long braid of the child preceding him. Another shot captures two elaborately dressed children, standing in front of a porcelain-vase shop, about to cross the street; behind them, people mill about and, in a quintessential San Francisco scene, a streetcar descends a steep cobblestone street. A third striking photograph, titled "Dead to the World," depicts a down-and-out man seated on a grimy stair in a back alley, eyes closed. In Genthe's book of photographs on Chinatown (text by Bill Irwin), this print is captioned "The Hop Fiend," a reference to people like this man who were hooked on opium, the street drug of choice in turn-of-the-century Chinatown. Genthe also took a number of other photos (not in this series) depicting the seamier and sometimes criminal side of San Francisco's Chinatown.
  - "A Corner Crowd - Chinatown, San Francisco, 1898" (Offsite-box 1, Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
    13-1/8 x 10-1/8 inches; signed "Arnold Genthe" includes his studio label
  - "Dead to the World", undated (Offsite-box 1, Box 1, Folder 2)
    13-1/16 x 10-1/16 inches; signed "Arnold Genthe, N.Y."
  - [Four children walking down street holding one another's braids], undated (Offsite-box 1, Box 1, Folder 3)
    9-1/8 x 12-3/8 inches
  - "In Old Chinatown, San Francisco", undated (Offsite-box 1, Box 1, Folder 4)
    12-11/15 x 8-3/4 inches
  - "In San Francisco's Chinatown, 1900" (Offsite-box 1, Box 1, Folder 5)
    13-3/16 x 9-7/8 inches; signed "Arnold Genthe"; includes his studio label
  - [Man holding baby, with another man and two children], undated (Offsite-box 1, Box 1, Folder 6)
    11-3/8 x 8-1/8 inches
  - [Man with two children in imperial costume], undated (Offsite-box 1, Box 2, Folder 7)
    13-3/8 x 8-15/16 inches; signed "Arnold Genthe, N.Y."; includes his studio label
  - [Small boy leaning against door post], undated (Offsite-box 1, Box 2, Folder 8)
    13-1/16 x 9-1/4 inches; signed "Arnold Genthe, N.Y."; "San Francisco, Chinatown" inscribed on verso
  - [Two children in imperial costume in front of vase shop], undated (Offsite-box 1, Box 2, Folder 9)
    8-13/16 x 13-5/16 inches
  - [Two men, one in imperial costume], undated (Offsite-box 1, Box 2, Folder 10)
    13-7/16 x 7-1/4 inches
  - [Two young children in imperial costume], undated (Offsite-box 1, Box 2, Folder 11)
    12-13/16 x 6-1/4 inches
  - [Woman with child in imperial costume], undated (Offsite-box 1, Box 2, Folder 12)
    12-7/8 x 10-1/16 inches; signed "Arnold Genthe, N.Y."
- Series II: Portraits
  Series II encompasses the better part of Arnold Genthe's career as a photographer, and fills Boxes 3 through 9. Arranged alphabetically by sitter. Unidentified persons are listed at the end, alphabetically by description.
  Genthe began shooting portraits while still living in San Francisco, in 1906; most of his portraiture, however, was done in New York City, where he resided from 1911 until just before his death in 1942. Some of the portraits are classic studio shots, the subjects posed with studio draping (satiny or filmy wraps for the women) against curtained backdrops. These more "serious" portraits include such society and political luminaries as Mary Astor, Sara Delano Roosevelt, and Harry S. Truman, the latter a color portrait (probably taken between 1935 and 1942) in which the then-U.S. senator is seated in a garden with Josef Stalin and other leaders. Actors and artists figured largely both as Genthe's subjects and as his friends, and these portraits are among his most playful and affectionate. Henry Miller mugs in Revolutionary-era costume. A young Jack London, in white shirt and tie, is handsome and rumpled, looking thoroughly modern. Mary Pickford is all flowers and lace, very much "America's Sweetheart." The actress Jeanne Eagels, in flowing robe, laughs with delight as she holds aloft a small dog. A bearded Ezra Pound looks fierce and independent, an artist of no pretension sitting for his portrait in plaid shirt and woolly vest. But perhaps most striking and enduring in this series are Genthe's portraits of Greta Garbo and Edna St. Vincent Millay. The great Garbo is, as ever, her dramatically aloof self; in one exquisite shot she is seen in profile, head tilted back, neck impossibly long; in another, she faces forward, a tragedian with hand grasping throat. The poet and playwright Edna St. Vincent Millay, in an early portrait, is luminous in a simple, sailor-style linen dress, framed by a magnolia tree in bloom. Prints in the series range from about 6 by 5 inches to 17 by 14 inches.
  - Anglin, Margaret, undated (Offsite-box 2, Box 3, Folder 13)
    12 x 8-7/8 inches
  - "Anita Zahn in a Garden" [color print], undated (Offsite-box 2, Box 3, Folder 14)
    7-1/4 x 8-13/16 inches; signed "Arnold Genthe, N.Y."
    See also: Box 13, Folder 104
  - Arden, Elizabeth, undated (Offsite-box 2, Box 3, Folder 13)
    13-1/16 x 8-1/8 inches; signed "Arnold Genthe, N.Y."
  - Astor, Mary, undated (Offsite-box 2, Box 3, Folder 16)
    12-1/2 x 8-1/16 inches
  - Atherton, Gertrude, undated (Offsite-box 2, Box 3, Folder 17)
    12-15/16 x 9-3/4 inches
  - Austin, Mary, undated (Offsite-box 2, Box 3, Folder 18)
    13-3/8 x 9-7/16
  - Campbell, Mrs. Patrick (Beatrice Stella Cornwallis-West), undated (Offsite-box 2, Box 3, Folder 19)
    9-1/8 x 11-15/16 inches
  - Chaliapin, Fyodor [being sculpted by Davidson, Jo], undated (Offsite-box 2, Box 3, Folder 20)
    8-7/8 x 13-1/8 inches
  - Chaliapin, Fyodor [with three other Russian artists], undated (Offsite-box 2, Box 3, Folder 21)
    8 x 11 inches
  - Chatterton, Ruth, undated (Offsite-box 2, Box 4, Folder 22)
    12-10/16 x 8-3/8 inches
  - Cole, George Watson, 1920, Mar. 6 (Offsite-box 2, Box 4, Folder 23)
    9-9/16 x 7-1/16 inches; signed "Arnold Genthe, N.Y."
  - Cowl, Jane, undated (Offsite-box 2, Box 4, Folder 24)
    12-3/16 x 8-15/16 inches
  - Day, Juliette [in play Yellow Jacket], undated (Offsite-box 2, Box 4, Folder 25)
    13-3/16 x 9-7/8 inches
  - Dragonette, Jessica, undated (Offsite-box 2, Box 4, Folder 26)
    13-3/8 x 8-15/16 inches
  - Eagels, Jeanne, undated (Offsite-box 2, Box 4, Folder 27)
    12-1/2 x 8-15/16 inches
  - Eames, Emma, undated (Offsite-box 2, Box 4, Folder 28)
    12-15/16 x 8-3/16 inches
  - Galsworthy, John, [1940-1942] (Offsite-box 2, Box 4, Folder 29)
    13-3/8 x 9-7/16 inches; signed "Arnold Genthe, N.Y."; "early 1940s" inscribed on verso
  - Garbo, Greta [facing front], undated (Offsite-box 3, Box 5, Folder 30)
    13-3/16 x 9-5/8 inches; signed "Arnold Genthe, N.Y."
  - Garbo, Greta [left profile], undated (Offsite-box 3, Box 5, Folder 31)
    12-7/8 x 9-5/16 inches; signed "Arnold Genthe, N.Y."
  - Garbo, Greta [left profile], undated (Offsite-box 3, Box 5, Folder 32)
    17-1/16 x 13-5/16 inches; signed "Arnold Genthe, N.Y."
  - Garbo, Greta [hand at throat], undated (Offsite-box 3, Box 5, Folder 33)
    11-5/16 x 10-1/16 inches
  - Hassam, Childe, undated (Offsite-box 3, Box 5, Folder 34)
    13-1/2 x 9-15/16 inches
  - Kennedy, Madge, undated (Offsite-box 3, Box 5, Folder 35)
    11-3/8 x 8-7/8 inches
  - Ladd, Schuyler [in play "Yellow Jacket"], undated (Offsite-box 3, Box 5, Folder 36)
    12-13/16 x 9-11/16 inches
  - Landi, Elissa, undated (Offsite-box 3, Box 5, Folder 37)
    12-5/8 x 8-5/16 inches; Genthe's studio label on verso
  - Le Gallienne, Eva, undated (Offsite-box 3, Box 6, Folder 38)
    10-1/4 x 7-13/16 inches
  - London, Jack, undated (Offsite-box 3, Box 6, Folder 39)
    13 x 10-1/8 inches; signed "Arnold Genthe, N.Y."
  - Losch, Tilly, undated (Offsite-box 3, Box 6, Folder 40)
    12-15/16 x 10-3/8 inches
    See also: Box 12, Folders 96 and 97
  - Louise, Anita, undated (Offsite-box 3, Box 6, Folder 41)
    12-13/16 x 8-7/8 inches
  - Margo, undated (Offsite-box 3, Box 6, Folder 42)
    12-11/16 x 8-15/16 inches
  - McCormack, John, undated (Offsite-box 3, Box 6, Folder 43)
    13-1/4 x 10-1/8 inches
  - Millay, Edna St. Vincent, undated (Offsite-box 3, Box 6, Folder 44)
    12-9/16 x 10 inches
  - Miller, Henry [in Revolutionary-era costume], undated (Offsite-box 3, Box 6, Folder 45)
    9-3/4 x 4-1/2 inches; signed "Arnold Genthe, S.F."; autographed by Miller
  - Miller, Henry, undated (Offsite-box 3, Box 6, Folder 46)
    9-13/16 x 4-7/8 inches; signed "Arnold Genthe, S.F."; autographed by Miller
  - Mollison, Amy, undated (Offsite-box 4, Box 7, Folder 47)
    13 x 9-5/16 inches
  - "New Orleans Mammy", undated (Offsite-box 4, Box 7, Folder 48)
    13-1/16 x 9-7/16 inches
  - O'Brien-Moore, Erin, undated (Offsite-box 4, Box 7, Folder 49)
    13 x 8-3/4 inches
  - Pickford, Mary, undated (Offsite-box 4, Box 7, Folder 50)
    13-1/4 x 8-7/8 inches
  - Pickford, Mary, undated (Offsite-box 4, Box 7, Folder 51)
    13-1/4 x 9-13/16 inches
  - Pound, Ezra, undated (Offsite-box 4, Box 7, Folder 52)
    13-1/2 x 10-1/8 inches
  - Roosevelt, Sara Delano (Mrs. James), undated (Offsite-box 4, Box 7, Folder 53)
    13-1/4 x 10-1/16 inches; signed "Arnold Genthe, N.Y."
  - Roosevelt, Sara Delano (Mrs. James), undated (Offsite-box 4, Box 7, Folder 54)
    13-7/16 x 9-13/16 inches; signed "Arnold Genthe, N.Y."
  - Sharaff, Irene [Black-and-white print], undated (Offsite-box 4, Box 8, Folder 55)
    13-1/4 x 9-3/4 inches
  - Sharaff, Irene [Half-tone print], undated (Offsite-box 4, Box 8, Folder 56)
    6-3/8 x 4-3/8 inches
  - Stokowski, Leopold, undated (Offsite-box 4, Box 8, Folder 57)
  - Terry, Ellen, Dame, undated (Offsite-box 4, Box 8, Folder 58)
    13-7/16 x 10-3/16 inches
  - Truman, Harry S. [with Stalin and other leaders; color print], undated (Offsite-box 4, Box 8, Folder 59)
    8-3/16 x 10-5/16 inches
  - Wald, Lillian D., undated (Offsite-box 4, Box 8, Folder 60)
    9-1/2 x 7-1/4 inches
  - Unidentified
    - [Actor, portraying Cardinal Richelieu?; color print], undated (Offsite-box 4, Box 8, Folder 61)
      9-9/16 x 7 inches
    - [Actress; half-tone print], undated (Offsite-box 4, Box 8, Folder 62)
      7-1/4 x 5-1/16 inches
    - "Chinese Theatre, New York", undated (Offsite-box 5, Box 9, Folder 63)
      10-7/8 x 12-9/16 inches
    - [Chinese woman and child; color print], undated (Offsite-box 5, Box 9, Folder 64)
      8-1/2 x 5-3/8 inches
    - [Man in costume, Chinese Theatre, N.Y.], undated (Offsite-box 5, Box 9, Folder 65)
      13-9/16 x 10-1/4 inches
    - [Man in naval uniform], undated (Offsite-box 5, Box 9, Folder 66)
      9-1/8 x 5-1/8 inches; signed "Arnold Genthe"
    - [Turn-of-the-century woman with baby], undated (Offsite-box 5, Box 9, Folder 67)
      8-15/16 x 5 inches
    - [Two girls; color print], undated (Offsite-box 5, Box 9, Folder 68)
      7-1/4 x 8-9/16 inches
    - [Two girls; color print], undated (Offsite-box 5, Box 9, Folder 69)
      7-7/16 x 9-1/8 inches
    - [Woman with Chinese scroll; half-tone print], undated (Offsite-box 5, Box 9, Folder 70)
      6-1/2 x 4-15/16 inches; "Arnold Genthe" typeset below print
- Series III: Landscapes
  Series III is arranged into two subseries: Domestic Views - United States; and Foreign Views - Guatemala; thereunder it is arranged alphabetically by title or description of view. Each subseries is distinct in both style and composition (Domestic Views are in color, Foreign Views in black and white), having been taken at very different points in Genthe's career; the uniting factor is that both are of landscapes.
  Domestic Views - United States are among the last prints Genthe made. In these, he experiments with the newest photographic technique, color photography, which was introduced for transparencies in 1935, just seven years before Genthe's death. It is estimated, then, that these were all taken between 1935 and 1942. Prints range from about 6 by 9 inches to 10 by 8 inches.
  In contrast to Genthe's culturally significant shots of turn-of-the-century Chinatown or his dramatic portraits of actresses, dancers, and socialites, these prints are rather less accomplished from a technical point of view. Most are of gardens and trees, a friend's terrace, and a rolling landscape. Only one was taken at night, a colorful explosion of fireworks over the water.
  Foreign Views - Guatemala appear to have been taken in 1927 (most of the photos are dated as such). The prints range from approximately 6 inches by 8 inches to 9 1/2 inches by 8 inches. It is likely they were shot in the city of Antigua, which, as Genthe notes in his autobiography, he was "particularly eager to explore"; the mountains in the background of several photographs further indicate this may be Antigua, a city that is set in a valley and surrounded by volcanic mountains. Many of the ten photographs in this subseries feature half-ruined cathedrals. In addition to capturing the ruined churches, Genthe also records some scenes of daily life in 1920s Guatemala: a man leading his oxen as they haul a cart; a woman (parcels balanced on her head) walking with a small boy past a cathedral; a barely clothed child standing on a dock at the edge of the water, palm trees waving overhead.
  - Domestic Views - United States
    - "Autumn Maple", undated (Offsite-box 5, Box 10, Folder 71)
      6-3/4 x 9-1/8 inches; signed "Arnold Genthe, N.Y."
    - [Blooming rhododendrons], undated (Offsite-box 5, Box 10, Folder 72)
      7 x 9-5/16 inches
    - [Fair or expo building with palm trees and U.S. flag], undated (Offsite-box 5, Box 10, Folder 73)
      8-5/8 x 5-5/8 inches; original hanging mount from 1940 exhibition included in folder
    - [Fireworks over the water], undated (Offsite-box 5, Box 10, Folder 74)
      7-3/16 x 5-3/8 inches
    - [Garden], undated (Offsite-box 5, Box 10, Folder 75)
      9-9/16 x 7-3/8 inches
    - [House and lily pond], undated (Offsite-box 5, Box 10, Folder 76)
      5-7/8 x 8-13/16 inches; signed "Arnold Genthe, N.Y."
    - "In the Shenandoah Valley, Virginia", undated (Offsite-box 5, Box 10, Folder 77)
      7-5/16 x 9-3/8 inches; signed "Arnold Genthe, N.Y."
    - "Lake at Myron C. Taylor's Country Place", undated (Offsite-box 5, Box 10, Folder 78)
      5-7/16 x 8-3/8 inches; signed "Arnold Genthe, N.Y."
    - "Terrace in the Albert Herter Garden", undated (Offsite-box 5, Box 10, Folder 79)
      7-1/2 x 9-5/16 inches
    - "The Woodhouse Water Garden", undated (Offsite-box 5, Box 10, Folder 80)
      9-3/8 x 7-9/16 inches; signed "Arnold Genthe, N.Y."; includes his studio label
  - Foreign Views -- Guatemala
    - [Child on dock, palm trees], 1927 (Offsite-box 6, Box 11, Folder 81)
      8-7/8 x 6-5/8 inches; "Guatemala, 1927" inscribed on verso
    - [Cupola of cathedral], undated (Offsite-box 6, Box 11, Folder 82)
      8-15/16 x 7-1/16 inches; "Guatemala, 1927" inscribed on verso
    - [Debris inside ruined cathedral], 1927 (Offsite-box 6, Box 11, Folder 83)
      9-7/16 x 7-7/16 inches; "Guatemala, 1927" inscribed on verso
    - [Interior of ruined cathedral], 1927 (Offsite-box 6, Box 11, Folder 84)
      9-3/8 x 7-5/16 inches; "Guatemala, 1927" inscribed on verso
    - [Man with oxen], 1927 (Offsite-box 6, Box 11, Folder 85)
      7-3/16 x 9-1/16 inches; "Guatemala, 1927" inscribed on verso
    - [Men in overgrown courtyard], 1927 (Offsite-box 6, Box 11, Folder 86)
      7-1/16 x 9-3/8 inches; "Guatemala, 1927" inscribed on verso
    - [Statue of Western female figure], 1927 (Offsite-box 6, Box 11, Folder 87)
      9-1/16 x 7-5/16 inches; "Guatemala, 1927" inscribed on verso
    - [Stone cathedral], undated (Offsite-box 6, Box 11, Folder 88)
      6-1/4 x 8 inches; "Guatemala" inscribed on verso
    - [Trees in front of cathedral], 1927 (Offsite-box 6, Box 11, Folder 89)
      6-15/16 x 9-1/16 inches; "Guatemala, 1927" inscribed on verso
    - [Woman and boy carrying parcels past cathedral], undated (Offsite-box 6, Box 11, Folder 90)
      9-5/8 x 7-9/16 inches; "Guatemala" inscribed on verso
- Series IV: Dancers